Guide to the Foster Hall Collection, 1800-1952 CAM.FHC.2011.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Foster Family, 1800-1952; II.
  - William B. Foster Papers, 1814-1955; 10.
    - War of 1812 Correspondence and Transactions, 1.
      - Payment transaction sheet, Mechanics Bank, signed by William Foster, November 9, 1814; D.6
      - Letter from Commissary General's Office to William Foster, November 28, 1814; D.7
      - Memorandum of Agreement between William Foster and Reuben Neal, January 20, 1815; D.8
      - Summary of proposals and purchases, December 17, 1814; D.9
      - Letter from Commissary General to William Foster, December 31, 1814; D.10
      - Letter from Col. John Miller to William Foster, January 2, 1815; D.11
      - Letter from Commissary General's to William Foster, January 21, 1815; D.12
      - Letter from Washington DC Military Supply Officer to William Foster, January 26, 1815; D.13
      - Letter from Commissary General to William Foster, January 29, 1815; D.14
      - Letter from Col. John Miller to William Foster, February 10, 1815; D.15
      - Returns of Ordnance Dept. needs; Capt. Woolley, February 11, 1815; D.16
      - Ordnance Dept. Purchase Sheet; Capt. Woolley signed, March 1, 1815; D.17
      - Letter from Colonel John Miller to William Foster, March 24, 1815; D.18
      - Ordnance Dept. Purchase sheet; Capt. Woolley signed, March 30, 1815; D.19
      - Requisition for clothing, Jacob Cormack to William Foster, April 3, 1815; D.20
      - Requisition for summer clothing, Jacob Cormack to William Foster, April 10, 1815; D.21
      - Request for equipment: Col. John Miler to William Foster, April 20, 1815; D.22
      - Requisition for hospital stores; Col. John Miller to William Foster, April 20, 1815; D.23
      - Requisition for clothing; Lt. McGunnegle to William Foster, April 25, 1815; D.24
      - Requisition for clothing; Jacob McCormack to William Foster, Mary 4, 1815; D.25
      - Clothing requisition; Thomas Helms to William Foster, May 4, 1815; D.26
      - Clothing requisition: Thomas Helms to William Foster, May 4, 1815; D.27
      - Letter from Thomas Horne to William Foster, May 5, 1815; D.28
      - Clothing requisition; Jacob Cormack to William Foster, May 8, 1815; D.29
      - Letter from Brig. Gen. Bipell to William Foster; equipment requisition, May 17, 1815; D.30
      - Clothing requisition; J.M. Aebrashel to William Foster, June 5, 1815; D.31
      - Letter from Capt. Woolley to William Foster, July 11, 1815; D.32
    - Papers Relating to Federal Court Case, U.S. vs. William Foster, 2.
      This section is composed of papers dealing with the Federal Court Case, U.S. v. William Foster, a case in which Foster argued for years that the U.S. government owed him money for services rendered and personal money used during his years as a commissary agent. These papers contain documents dealing prominently with cases in 1822 and 1850.
      - Series of handwritten documents dealing with Foster's advances for the federal government, 1814, 1815, 1822; D.33
      - USA vs. William Foster, copy of docket entries, January 9, 1822; D.34
      - Report of committee of claims, constructed by J.H. Eaton, petitioner, January 26, 1826; D.35
      - Article from Pittsburgh Mercury on paper, October 23, 1822; D.36
      - Letter from Amasa Stetson to William Foster, November 10,1822; D.37
      - USA vs. William Foster, court documents, December 6, 1822; D.38
      - Printed extract from publication on case of William Foster, undated; D.39
      - Letter from John Snowden to Senate and House of Representatives, USA, January 1, 1836; D.40
      - Signatures of support for William Foster (accompanied D.40), January 1, 1836; D.41
      - Notes on a 'civic parade,', January 4; D.42
      - Brief on case of William Foster; signed, J.S. Eaton, undated; D.43
      - Publication and letter concerning Amasa Stetson's case, February 7, 1846; D.44
      - J.H. Eaton to Senator Cameron regarding Foster's claim (2), February 28, 1846; D.45
      - Sheet of monetary tabulations, November 1849; D.46
      - Court papers from Pittsburgh, regarding government payment, undated; D.47
      - William Foster to U.S. Senate and House of Representatives, January 1850; D.48
      - Monetary transaction slip; court case reference, undated; D.49
      - Contract signed by William Foster; asserts that Abraham Farquhar has power to pursue the court case, March 15, 1850; D.50
      - Account of USA vs. William Foster (original and 3 duplicates), April 3, 1850; D.51
      - Account of USA vs. William Foster; enclosed in envelope to Honorable D. Hubbard, April 3, 1850; D.52
      - Letter from William Foster to A.M. Farquhar, April 30, 1850; D.53
      - Tabulated amounts stemming from Foster's service and court fees, 1850s; D.54
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to his sister, December 2, 1861; D.55
      - Contract signed by Horatio King outlining terms for William Foster's case; Jesse Thornton signed also (2), March 11, 1862; D.56
      - Letter from Henrietta Foster to Morrison Foster (business card included), March 21, 1862; D.57
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to John Wilson, February 16, 1867; D.58
      - John Wilson to Morrison Foster, March 4, 1867; D.59
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to Honorable J.R. McClintock, June 8, 1876; D.60
      - Letter from Jesse Thornton to unknown, March 1, 1878; D.61
      - Newspaper clipping on Col. John Miller, April 14, 1882; D.62
    - Land Warrants of Lawrenceville, 3.
      This section deals with William Foster's prominent role in establishing the community of Lawrenceville in modern day Pittsburgh, Pa. Most of these documents are land warrant receipts and notes of the first inhabitants of the area, many of whom were soldiers who were reimbursed with land grants for their service during the War of 1812.
      - Receipt of money paid on estate of John A. Kritze, signed John Scotte, register, February 27, 1849; D.63
      - U.S. Army Pay Dept., award back pay to father of deceased, A. Kritzer, signed by William Foster, October 15, 1849; D.64
      - Letter from Jesse Kilgore to William Foster regarding Kritzer back pay, October 17, 1849; D.65
      - Letter from Jesse Kilgore to William Foster regarding Kritzer back pay, November 16, 1849; D.66
      - Letter from John Kilgore to William Foster regarding Kritzer back pay, March 8, 1850; D.67
      - Register Francis Springer to 'Sir' (from Land Office), June 26, 1851; D.68
      - Statement proclaiming that John Schwartz appoints William Foster as his attorney, August 5, 1851; D.69
      - Letter form John Schwartz to William Foster, August 11, 1851; D.70
      - Letter from John Wilson (pension office) to William Foster, September 26, 1851; D.71
      - Letter from W. Buehler to Stephen C. Foster, November 26, 1851; D.72
      - Letter from W. Buehler to William Foster, November 26, 1851; D.73
      - Land Warrant receipt no. 75.445, signed Jacob Little, February 23, 1852; D.74
      - Notice: Land Warrant for Andrew Black; attach: document stating Andrew Black has appointed Thomas Hamilton as his attorney, March 3, 1852; D.75
      - Letter from G.E. Arnolds to Morrison Foster; Land Warrant 74.642 receipt, May 3, 1852; D.76
      - Land Warrant receipt of Thomas Hickenloper; attached to Document that states that William Foster is selling him land, May 29, 1848; D.77
      - Land Warrant receipt 41.348 signed by John Ferrel, May 17, 1852; D.78
      - Land warrant purchase receipt, signed by A.S. Bell, June 2, 1852; D.79
      - Land warrant receipt 44.616 signed by Harry Quest, June 5, 1852; D.80
      - Land warrant receipt for John Dietz, August 16, 1852; D.81
      - Land warrant receipt no. 17.816 signed by Joshua Cook, September 30, 1852; D.82
      - Collection notice for Morrison Foster, no date; D.83
      - Land Warrant receipt 17.315 signed by James Patterson, November 1, 1852; D.84
      - Letter from Myron Gray to William Foster, January 18, 1853; D.85
      - Surgeon's certificate of ordinary disability; Myron Gray, U.S. Army, April 27, 1848; D.86
      - Jesse Kilgore to William Foster, concerning Kritzer back-pay, April 4, 1853; D.87
      - Letter from Robert Fleming to Jesse Kilgore, April 27, 1853; D.88
      - Letter from Jesse Kilgore to Robert Fleming, May 4, 1863; D.89
      - Indiscernible land warrant notes (1 of 4), 1822; D.90
      - Indiscernible land warrant notes (2 of 4), undated; D.91
      - Indiscernible land warrant notes (3 of 4) W. Foster signed, undated; D.92
      - Indiscernible land warrant notes (4 of 4), undated; D.93
      - Typed soldier rosters taken from William Foster's Soldier's Agent Book; typed by Evelyn Morneweck (2 copies), undated; D.94
    - Morrison Foster: Personal Correspondence, 4.
      This section is composed of the personal correspondence of Morrison Foster, a son of William B. Foster and older brother to Stephen Collins Foster. Besides the general correspondence found here, a small group of Valentines are also present. Also of note is the letter from Andrew Carnegie to Morrison Foster, dated 11/24/1897.
      - Letter from Henry Murray to Morrison Foster, June 7, 1838; D.95
      - Hannah S. to Morrison Foster, April 23, 1846; D.96
      - Letter from I. Blair to Morrison Foster, April 23, 1846; D.97
      - Letter from Hannah S. to Morrison Foster, January 26, 1847; D.98
      - Letter from Dan Betzhoover to Morrison Foster, December 15, 1847; D.99
      - Letter from Lt. H.B. Field to Morrison Foster, March 30, 1848; D.100
      - Letter from Mary Anderson to Morrison Foster, July 29, 1848; D.101
      - An announcement of the Knights of the Square Table, January 21, 1849; D.102
      - Letter from Dan Betzhoover to Morrison Foster, February 8, 1849; D.103
      - Letter from Dan Betzhoover to Morrison Foster (retyped by Evelyn Morneweck), February 8, 1849; D.104
      - Letter from Mary Anderson to Morrison Foster, November 23, 1849; D.105
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster, July 11, 1850; D.106
      - Letter from Thomas Blair to Morrison Foster, December 1, 1850; D.107
      - Letter from Oliver W. Barnes to Morrison Foster, December 13, 1850; D.108
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster, July 12, 1851; D.109
      - Letter from J.H. Reid to Morrison Foster, March 27, 1852; D.110
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster (retyped by Evelyn Morneweck), January 14, 1853; D.111
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster, January 14, 1853; D.112
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster, January 22, 1853; D.113
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster (retyped by Evelyn Morneweck), January 22, 1853; D.114
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster, February 8, 1853; D.115
      - Letter from Richard Cowan to Morrison Foster, April 17, 1853; D.116
      - Letter from S. Bateman to Morrison Foster, September 18, 1853; D.117
      - Letter from Ed Collier to Morrison Foster, January 28, 1855; D.118
      - Letter from R. Biddle Roberts to Morrison Foster, September 17, 1856; D.119
      - Letter from N.J. Carey to Morrison Foster, January 3, 1858; D.120
      - Letter from K.J. Lambert to Morrison Foster, June 27, 1859; D.121
      - Letter from M.K. Jesup to Morrison Foster, November 11, 1859; D.122
      - Letter from Gilead Smith to Morrison Foster, February 20, 1860; D.123
      - Letter from William Muller to Morrison Foster, September 13, 1860; D.124
      - Letter from Governor Samuel Black (Nebraska) to Morrison Foster, December 13, 1860; D.125
      - Letter from Gov. Samuel Black to Morrison Foster, March 18, 1861; D.126
      - Letter from Samuel Randall to Morrison Foster, August 29, 1861; D.127
      - Printed speech of Rep. George Pendleton, September 15, 1864; D.128
      - Letter from George Pendleton to Morrison Foster, July 18, 1875; D.129
      - Letter from M. Hordoch to Morrison Foster, February 6, 1880; D.130
      - 124th Robert Burns Celebration Pamphlet, January 25, 1883; D.131
      - Letter from Mary Drummston to Morrison Foster, August 29, 1886; D.132
      - Letter from Mary Drummston to Morrison Foster, August 24, 1886; D.133
      - Letter from Mary Drummston to Morrison Foster, August 30, 1886; D.134
      - Letter from Mary Drummston to Morrison Foster, September 9, 1886; D.135
      - Letter from Mary Drummston to Morrison Foster, September 16, 1886; D.136
      - Letter from Mary Drummston to Morrison Foster, September 22, 1886; D.137
      - Photograph of William Haslitt, September 9, 1887; D.138
      - Letter from Sir Edwin Arnold to Morrison Foster, May 23, 1894; D.139
      - Letter from Andrew Carnegie to Morrison Foster, November 24, 1897; D.140
      - Composition by Thomas Blair, undated; D.141
      - Valentine from Julia Murray to Morrison Foster, February 14, 1847; D.142
      - Valentine from Julia Murray to Morrison Foster, retyped by Evelyn Morneweck, February 14, 1847; D.143
      - Valentine from Morrison Foster to Julia Murray, retyped by Evelyn Morneweck, February 14, 1847; D.144
      - Valentine from Thomas Blair to Julia Murray, retyped by Evelyn Morneweck, February 14, 1847; D.145
      - Valentine from J.C. Blair to Julia Murray, retyped by Evelyn Morneweck, 1847 or 1848; D.146
      - Valentine from J.C. Blair to Julia Murray, retyped by Evelyn Morneweck, 1846, 1847, or 1848; D.147
      - Valentine from Julie McIlvaine to Evelyn Morneweck, February 6, 1939; D.148
      - Valentine from Evelyn Morneweck to Julie McIlvaine, February 14, 1939; D.149
      - Valentine from Evelyn Morneweck to Julie McIlvaine, February 24, 1939; D.150
    - Morrison Foster: Business Correspondence, 5.
      This section contains the business correspondence of Morrison Foster. Most of these letters tell of Morrison's various business transactions and partnerships during the 1850s and late 1860s.
      - Letter from P. McCormick to Morrison Foster, May 5, 1848; D.151
      - Letter from P. McCormick to Morrison Foster, May 11, 1848; D.152
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to P. McCormick, December 20, 1849; D.153
      - Newspaper: Allegheny Daily Enterprise, January 1, 1851; D.154
      - Annual dues for young men's Mercantile Library Association and Mechanic's Institute, January 1, 1852; D.155
      - McCormick notice to Kramer and Rahm, September 16, 1852; D.156
      - Promissory note to pay W.W. Wilson from Morrison Foster, October 16, 1852; D.157
      - Formal invitation to the "Assembly Ball", February 1, 1853; D.158
      - Payment of "Assembly Ball"; W.S. Haven to managers of the ball, undated; D.159
      - Morrison Foster payment to John Crassan, undated; D.160
      - Tabulation of expenses, July 4, 1853; D.161
      - Payment receipt signed by Jesse Thornton, undated; D.162
      - Letter from P. McCormick to Morrison Foster, August 22, 1853; D.163
      - Letter from P. McCormick to Morrison Foster, October 1863; D.164
      - Instructions for payment of Morrison Foster and Jesse Thornton, October 1853; D.165
      - Letter from W.W. Wilson to Morrison Foster, October 14, 1853; D.166
      - Receipt of costs for "Assembly Ball", February 2, 1854; D.167
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to N. Young, February 3, 1854; D.168
      - Payment for Jesse Thornton, signed by J. Thornton, February 13, 1854; D.169
      - Letter from P. Schoenberger to Morrison Foster, March 19, 1854; D.170
      - Payment receipt, signed by Eliza Foster, April 13, 1854; D.171
      - Receipt of payment by Morrison Foster, June 30, 1854; D.172
      - Receipt, signed by Eliza Foster, July 20, 1854; D.173
      - P. McCormick acknowledges Morrison Foster as his representation for one year, September 28, 1854; D.174
      - Statement of sale signed by Morrison Foster, December 13, 1854; D.175
      - Letter from D.M. Foster to brothers, December 28, 1854; D.176
      - P. McCormick; receipt from Morrison Foster, January 15, 1855; D.177
      - Letter from Major Thomas Martin to Morrison Foster, April 30, 1855; D.178
      - Quartermaster's Office -- Pittsburgh, May 11, 1855; D.179
      - Mr. Dowd of the Pittsburgh Club to Morrison Foster, June 1855; D.180
      - Morrison Foster business dues, June 11, 1855; D.181
      - Newspaper notice; "Dissolution of Thornton and Foster partnership", undated; D.182
      - Payment for beverages by Morrison Foster, February 4, 1857; D.183
      - Letter from S. Jones to Morrison Foster, January 22, 1858; D.184
      - Letter from P. McCormick to Morrison Foster, undated; D.185
      - Letter from M.I. Stewart to Morrison Foster, January 22, 1859; D.186
      - Letter from A.B. McCalmont to Morrison Foster, January 22, 1859; D.187
      - Letter from R. Biddle Roberts to Morrison Foster, January; D.188
      - Letter from Captain Overton Carr to Thomas B. Florence, undated; D.189
      - Letter from Thomas B. Florence to Morrison Foster, February 19, 1859; D.190
      - Letter from Thomas B. Florence to Captain Overton Carr, February 19, 1859; D.191
      - Letter from Captain Overton Carr to Morrison Foster, February 20, 1859; D.192
      - Letter from Thomas Florence to Morrison Foster, March 1, 1859; D.193
      - Letter from John B. Guthrie to Morrison Foster, June 13, 1859; D.194
      - Letter from Thomas Blair to Morrison Foster, June 8, 1859; D.195
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to D.C. McCormick, November 18, 1859; D.196
      - Memorandum of agreement between William F. Carey and Schoenberger and Co., December 19, 1859; D.197
      - Ohio Union State Ticket (2 copies), 1863; D.198
      - Cuyahoga County Democratic Ticket (2 copies), 1863; D.199
      - National Democratic Ticket, 1864; D.200
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to A.W. Randall, October 1, 1866; D.201
      - Stock Account Statement, February 1, 1869; D.202
      - Stock Account Statement, February 27, 1869; D.203
      - Stock Account Statement, March 31, 1869; D.204
      - Stock Account Statement, April 30, 1869; D.205
      - Stock Account Statement, May 31, 1869; D.206
      - Stock Account Statement, June 30, 1869; D.207
      - Stock Account Statement, July 31, 1869; D.208
      - Stock Account Statement, August 31, 1869; D.209
      - Contract: Schoenberger & Co. and Morrison Foster, September 13, 1869; D.210
      - Stock Account statement, September 30, 1869; D.211
      - Letter from Schoenberger & Co. to Morrison Foster, October 5, 1869; D.212
      - Stock Account Statement, October 30, 1869; D.213
      - Stock Account Statement, November 30, 1869; D.214
      - Stock Account Statement, December 31, 1869; D.215
      - Schoenberger and Co. to Morrison Foster, February 16, 1871; D.216
      - Schoenberger & Co. to Morrison Foster, March 4, 1871; D.217
      - Booklet, Report: The Blair Iron and Steel Company, undated; D.218
      - J.L. Newberry to Morrison Foster, September 13, 1876; D.219
      - Typed excerpt from Allegheny Evening Mail, October 28, 1878; D.220
      - Postcard: Echo Valley, Utah, August 22, 1883; D.221
      - Newspaper article, "Complete List of Members of the Democratic County Organization", 1895; D.222
      - Article, Pittsburgh Gazette, January 4, 1895; D.223
      - Article, The Youngstown Telegraph, March 18, 1895; D.224
      - Article, The Pittsburgh Dispatch, "Bryan's Skate Across Country was a Marvel", 1896; D.225
      - Letter from Guild and Lord to Morrison Foster, undated; D.226
    - Morrison Foster: Inquiries; Grant's Hill and The Enterprise, 6.
      This section deals with Morrison Foster's inquiries into the Grant's Hill Foundry and his father's involvement during the War of 1812 with the naval vessel, The Enterprise. These letters largely are written during the 1880s.
      - Typed excerpts from 1824 edition of The Pittsburgh Gazette, D.227
      - Letter from Randolph Klein to Morrison Foster, March 27, 1880; D.228
      - Letter from John N. Bofinger to Morrison Foster, undated; D.229
      - Letter from D. Lowry to Morrison Foster, 1888; D.230
      - Letter from John A. Sargent to Morrison Foster, March 6, 1888; D.231
      - Postcard: Samuel Hay to Morrison Foster, March 9, 1888; D.232
      - Letter from John Matthews to Morrison Foster, March 13, 1888; D.233
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to War Department; response on back, May 14, 1888; D.234
      - Letter from Commissary General's office to Morrison Foster (2 copies of 1814 dispatches, response to inquiry), May 29, 1888; D.235
      - Letter from John Tweedale of War Department to unknown (probably Morrison Foster), June 8, 1888; D.236
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to chief clerk, Commissary General's Office, response on bottom, July 14, 1888; D.237
      - Letter from Morrison Foster to New Orleans subsistence department, response on back, July 18, 1888; D.238
      - Letter from L.E. Stofiel to Morrison Foster, February 24, 1891; D.239
    - Lawrenceville Burial Ground vs. War 17 School Board, 7.
      This section concerns itself with the Pittsburgh Ward 17 School and the issue of building upon the Lawrenceville Burial Ground, which was established by William B. Foster. The majority of these letters and clippings deal with the 1880's court battle between the two parties regarding building rights in the area on, and adjacent to, the burial ground.
      - Article, The Pittsburgh Dispatch, 1850; D.240
      - Small ad, no publication documentation, March 1882; D.241
      - Article, The Evening Chronicle, March 3, 1882; D.242
      - Article, The Pittsburg Leader, March 18, 1882; D.243
      - Article, The Pittsburg Leader, March 19, 1882; D.244
      - Article, The Daily Post, March 20, 1882; D.245
      - Article, The Daily Post, March 21, 1882; D.246
      - Article, The Pittsburgh Dispatch, March 21, 1882; D.247
      - Article, The Pittsburgh Dispatch, March 22, 1882; D.248
      - Article, no date, no documentation, undated; D.249
      - Article, no date, no documentation, undated; D.250
      - Letter from Ann Eliza to Morrison Foster, March 23, 1882; D.251
      - Letter from Ann Eliza to Morrison Foster, retyped by Evelyn Morneweck, March 23, 1882; D.252
      - Letter from George M. Dallas to Morrison Foster, March 24, 1882; D.253
      - Note on paper: address of Nathan Gunnegle, undated; D.254
      - Article, The Pittsburg Leader, March 26, 1882; D.255
      - Allegheny County Court of Common Pleas: Roger Jeffrey, William Moore, A.M. Mooreland, Morrison Foster v. City of Pittsburgh and 17th Ward School (2 copies), undated; D. 256
      - Article, The Daily Post, June 1, 1882; D.257
      - Supreme Court of Pennsylvania, publication, November 1882; D.258
      - Unintelligible document regarding the Lawrenceville Burial Ground Court Case, undated; D.259
      - Statement regarding the formation of the Lawrenceville Burial Ground Court Case, undated; D.260
      - Journal sheets of speech denouncing the 17th Ward School being allowed to build on the burial ground, 1882; D.261
      - Article, The Pittsburg Leader, February 4, 1883; D.262
      - Letter from A. Harbaugh to Morrison Foster, March 17, 1883; D.263
      - Article, no documentation, undated; D.264
      - Attorney Charles McKenna to Board of Directors, 17th Ward School District, March 29, 1883; D.265
      - Article, The Daily Post, May 7, 1883; D.266
      - Article, The Pittsburgh Evening Chronicle, May 30, 1883; D.267
      - Article, The Pittsburgh Dispatch, May 31, 1883; D.268
      - Letter from Nathaniel G. Gunnegle to nephew, Charles E. Barr, June 29, 1883; D.269
      - Letter from Nathaniel G. Gunnegle to nephew Charles E. Barr, retyped by Evelyn Morneweck (2 copies), June 29, 1883; D.270
      - Letter from Nathaniel G. Gunnegle to Morrison Foster, August 8, 1883; D.271
      - Letter from Nathaniel G. Gunnegle to Morrison Foster; retyped by Evelyn Morneweck (2 copies), August 8, 1883; D.272